Ken Song

Senior Web Developer

Nagoya, Japan | +81 52-251-6231 | kenofuniverse@gmail.com

Summary

I am a software engineer focused on web development. I have 8 years of experience in both startup and enterprise business environments building solutions where full-stack skills, creative thinking, and high attention to detail are key, and fast turnaround is paramount.

Employment History

Freelance Developer

2010 - PRESENT

Self-employed

Worked as a remote developer in lots of different teams and companies.

- Worked as a PHP developer
- Worked as a JavaScript developer
- Worked as a full stack developer with React, Angular and Node.js

Software Engineer, Lead Developer

2012 - 2013

Takamitsu Co.Ltd, Nagoya Japan

- Built e-commerce website for selling medical products
- Designed content structures from previously made designs and created custom WordPress themes based on provided HTML and CSS code.
- Built real-time web-based support platform for internal members and client use.
- Maintained and migrated a very large database.
- Wrote unit tests and integration tests for all features and bug fixes.

Education

Master of Engineering 2010 - 2012

Nagoya University, Japan

Bachelor of Engineering 2006 - 2010

Nagoya University, Japan

Skills

Languages

PHP, JavaScript, Node.js, HTML, CSS

Frameworks

WordPress, Laravel, Codeigniter, Symfony2, Smarty, Angular, Express

Libraries/APIs

React, jQuery, Node.js, cURL,

Facebook API, Youtube API

Paradigms

Agile Software Development, Model View Controller, REST, OOP

Storage

MySQL, JSON, NoSQL, Microsoft SQL Server, MongoDB

Other

RESTful Web Services, Git, DevOps

Recent Works

Senior WordPress Developer

2016 - PRESENT

ROSHI, LLC (https://www.lasikvisioninstitute.com)

- Built WordPress theme and plugins that are being used in all the company branch websites.
- Designed and modified database tables to be more optimized and be more quicker.
- Built solid back end interface for connecting several Leads APIs.
- Managed DevOps works for migrating company branch websites and its database.

Technologies: WordPress, PHP, MySQL, PHP Curl, DevOps

Senior WordPress Developer

2017 - PRESENT

Pattison Institute (https://www.pattisoninstitute.com)

- Fixed and customized an s2Member plugin to have more member levels and privileges.
- Installed SSL to the web hosting to ensure security.
- Made full-scale optimizations for better performance using the Total Cache WordPress plugin which significantly reduced loading time.
- Updated WordPress core and plugins and then fixed the compatibility issues.

Technologies: WordPress, HTML, PHP, MySQL

Senior React Developer

2016 - PRESENT

DigiPro, LLC

- Developed custom PHP framework from scratch
- Built page builder using React/Redux with best user experience from scratch
- Converted CRM dashboard to React and improved UX and speed
- Integrated the finance tracking service with existing acception React Developerounting systems.
- Enhanced the user experience using AJAX and front-end validation for form submission in Mailchimp and contact forms.
- Integrated eCommerce with custom CRM and third-party payment APIs.

Technologies: PHP, Symfony, React, Redux, MySQL, AJAX, Bootstrap, RESTful API

Full-stack JavaScript Engineer

2017 - 2018

Tether.io (https://www.tether.id)

- Built base components that are being used in all company projects
- Integrated draft.js WYSIWYG editor with React into a reusable library.
- Supported Math expressions and editor inside the WYSIWYG editor.
- Worked with legacy code on the server side, able to understand the principles behind it and make it work again.

Technologies: React.js, Redux, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB

Joomag, Inc (https://www.joomag.com/en)

- Built dashboard and its pages following the design pixel-perfect, achieving scalability and extensibility.
- Implemented the internalization using a React-i18n component and i18n-related WebPack plugins.
- Integrated external libraries like HighChart and Google Charts.

Technologies: React.js, Redux, HighCharts, i18n, Webpack, Ant Design

Senior Full Stack Developer for PayFac Project

2016 - 2018

PayScout (https://www.payscout.com)

- Built compliance management portal front end using Angular4 with bootstrap premium template (Inspinia)
- Implemented Auth2 using Node.js for both inner authentication and third party authentication.
- Implemented RESTful API for getting and setting data to Microsoft SQL database
- Defined highly reusable data table component with bunch of filters integrated using Angular4
- Established smart caching and restoring system using local storage for best UX
- · Made API testing for all API endpoints

Technologies: Angular 4, Bootstrap, Node.js, Auth2, RESTful API, Sequelize

Senior Web Developer

2013 - 2017

Verose, LLC

- Migrated HTTP servers from Apache to Nginx.
- Developed watermark feature for photos uploaded by users in HTML5 and PHP Symfony.
- Integrated payment gateways such as Mopay, Zong, and Paypal in customer platform (built with the Zend framework).
- Fixed PHP security issues for production sites (including: SQL injections, cross-site scripting, remote code execution, and more).
- Wrote API connectors for Apostrophe, an in-context CMS product built on the Symfony framework.

Technologies: PHP, Zend, Symfony, SQL, Apache, Nginx

Wordpress Developer

2012 - 2018

Itabix, Inc (https://itabix.com)

- Completely redesigned and currently maintaining the network of WordPress sites, emphasizing speed, optimization, and usability.
- Turned beautiful Photoshop designs into WordPress sites.
- Learned how to use WordPress as a framework for general application development, not just for blogging and static content.
- Built custom WordPress plugin for managing development, staging and production websites easily.

Technologies: PHP, WordPress, PSD to HTML, WordPress Theme, WordPress Plugins